Hello and welcome to AI Native DevCon by Tessl.
This is the fourth edition
of this conference, the second in person and the first in London.
We're at the Brewery in central London, near the Barbican Center.
And let's go in and take a look at some of the expo hall,
and we'll give you a flavor of what AIND DevCons are like. Follow me.
The AI Native Dev is a podcast for developers and engineering leads
at the cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts, Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple,
every week as we chat with the most exciting voices in AI
and tackle the biggest questions facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev.
Okay.
So here we are at the expo center of AI Native DevCon.
We're going to walk in. It's a break. It's busy.
Let's try and talk to some attendees.
So follow me.
And you can see the expo hall is packed full of people, full of attendees
and full of sponsors.
There are areas to get some free shirts and the sponsors going right round.
So let's find someone to talk to. Follow me.
Tell us a little bit about yourself. What's your name and who do you work for?
I have a couple of companies,
but the reason I'm here, I have a fintech startup I'm building alone.
Oh, nice.
Combining blockchain, public and private markets.
So I'm here to learn what are the tools available to make my life easier to
to expedite the process and to make the production process output more reliable.
So looking for tools and practices and processes.
What are some of the sessions that you've really enjoyed so far?
Max the guy from.
Max Furman.
No, no.
The Max Maximilian from Argentina.
Oh, yeah.
And Web MCP.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, I just remember his last name.
He was very interesting then. Dave. Dave.
Farley. Yeah. Dave Farley with in wave.
So I'm planning to try all those tools in my stack and see what I can.
Yeah. Very interesting.
And one of the things I learned with Dave Farley
is everyone has a different approach to doing,
to doing agentic development and coding.
And so Dave's some of the things that they were saying,
well, obviously really well for him and there's some other people
kind of like saying, oh yeah, I agree with this bit, but not that.
So I think it's really important for us to,
to find our own way, but learn from others who are doing this at scale.
As well.
One more session they got my attention is was Lubbock.
Yeah.
From the companies.
The different forgotten name.
But he's using Pi.
So I want to try that one as well.
So amazing. Amazing. Well, enjoy the rest of the conference.
Thanks for speaking. Awesome. Thank you. Sorry. Which one to
So? So, Chris, this is Chris Baty, one of our speakers.
Chris, tell us a little bit about yourself and what you presented this week.
Yeah.
So I've been an engineer for 20 years or so,
and what I've done over the last couple of years
is I've been building a product team within a consultancy,
so we've hired new people, we've tried to build products.
And so my talk was about like our lessons learned of adopting AI in that team
and what we're able to achieve, which we wouldn't
have been able to achieve I think, if we tried to do this five years ago.
Yeah, yeah.
And what are the kind of like
some of the key learnings that you would say
if you were to give advice to someone who is on this journey as well?
What are the key things that you wish you could have told you?
Avoid vanity metrics at all costs, like code, commits or tokens.
People who are using, have a look at your flow of delivery
right from idea to someone using your piece of software.
Don't stop at like commit or, you know, outputs.
Think about the actual outcomes you want your team
and find the friction, right?
Because it's not normally in code production.
For our experience, it's not even idea production like product management.
We've been pretty good at that.
Now the bottleneck for us is actually getting real people
to use our software and quickly feeding back on those.
So yeah.
And how well are you finding,
I guess, execs or senior folks within the engineering teams to
to accept those types of metrics over and above token usage actually,
like when it comes to it, the higher up you go, if you can talk
in the business outcomes like they love that right.
Outcomes over output.
Yeah, exactly.
Outcomes are outcomes over output.
So I'd say it's normally like I'd say like middle management
that are going for vanity metrics because they're easy to measure.
But if you say hey to your existing or higher ups like we can get
these customers doing this by this date, and that's the only measure of success.
I don't really care how many tokens you use, like
how many commits you make, how many other features that you build.
Because I think we're all like suffering from building features
that are not being used because it's so easy to build features now.
In fact, if you can improve your outcomes as hard as you can with with as fewer
tokens as you can use, even better as fewer features in your product, really,
because like we've all used on camera, I'm not going to name
any sessions that you've been to that you've thought have been really amazing,
or have you mostly been focusing on the on the hallway track?
Both, really.
I mean, we just went to the session about like measuring the impact of agents
and AI development on organizations and
like how people can become low performance or high performance.
But overall, I think it's been
like a really good conference with a nice balance of like,
we need a bit of hype, we need to get excited about our work.
But there's been a lot of like practical takeaways as well.
So people like dealing with reality.
Yeah, amazing. Well.
Thanks for joining us.
Thanks for speaking to us
and thanks for supporting the conference and AI Native Dev.
Tell us a little bit about yourself.
About what you do.
Okay.
I work at Train Guard on the AI automation team.
I've been dabbling with AI stuff since Copilot's first started telling me
what to do.
Tried to make that into a predictive text generator for functions, and ever since,
I've been sort of captivated
with making AI a productive tool for my development workflows.
Awesome.
I'm here to pick up on what the current trends and you know,
fields are in the industry among everyone that's.
In amazing.
And of course, we first met — Alan Pope introduced us,
and we first met at Starbucks like 18 months ago.
And other bad coffee establishments are available.
But you know, from when we first chatted to now,
what would you say are some of the biggest changes
in your working environment and style from a development point of view?
When we spoke back then, we were talking about the capability of the models,
and then shortly after that, the whole sort of MCP and agentic thing
kicked off.
So I think it's really the tooling around the models that has changed the most.
Obviously the model capability has improved significantly,
but I think the force multiplier has been the tooling around the models.
So skills, MCP servers, they've really sort of delivered
sort of recency of information to the models that really make them more,
much more capable. Amazing.
So I think that's the big thing for me.
And and other than my conference opening, what would you say is your highlight
for the for sessions? The sessions?
I don't know.
That's a tough one.
I think there's been a couple of the exhibitors that are interesting.
So the virtual SRE, I really like. The.
Interesting looks inside
your existing observability stack and acts like a historical SRE,
looking at where the issues were and automatically proposing fixes.
So I kind of like that. Which, which which was that?
Is it Autonomy AI. Oh yeah yeah yeah.
Yeah yeah. Awesome. We'll talk to them in a bit.
Martin, thank you for spending time with us.
Cheers.
Your name and what do you do?
My name is Ryan. I'm a tech lead.
Qwerty me very interesting. What are the.
What are the things that you've come to the AI Native DevCon to to to learn or
practice more about?
Yeah, I've come to potentially see gaps from what I know and what I don't know.
And I've identified a few gaps. Oh, awesome.
Would you mind sharing a couple of days with us?
Oh, sort of harnessing harnesses as a whole.
Yeah, that's a new concept to me.
And evals is something I'm very interested in.
For your context and. Awesome. Awesome.
What are the kind of things
that you feel like you can take away and try straight away?
Evals for sure.
Yeah,
we've got skills spread all over the place and kind of want to consolidate them.
Yeah, and look into the evals.
What would you say is some of the biggest problems around
skills, is it distribution.
Is it duping of skills.
But of duplication.
I'd say at work it's just skills
coming in too quickly and more on the mid to junior level.
They're not knowing about the skills they need to use it.
So it's a bit of it's consolidation in my opinion — consolidation.
And I guess it sounds like a little bit of education about knowing where to go.
Yeah that's great. Amazing. Amazing. Anything else you're looking forward to?
Anything else you got your name by in the workshops or sessions?
Next workshop.
Yes, it's the test. What's up?
Yeah.
I can't remember the name of it now.
Yeah, it's a test.
Test strategy, I think. Oh, awesome. Awesome.
Yeah, yeah.
Is that the one with Brooke and Macie?
Maybe. Perhaps from Tessl? Yes. Yeah. Awesome.
That's going to be a great workshop. Excellent.
Thank you very much for being with us and the rest of the conference.
Like.
We have Manny Saka here.
Long-term supporter of the AI Native Dev.
Devin, it's great to see you here at the conference as well.
So, Manny, tell us a little bit about your background.
Tell us a little bit about why you're here.
What are you trying to learn at the conference? Definitely.
So I'm a software engineer turned AI/ML engineer.
I've got a history of 25 years of software engineering, and in the last
8 to 10 years, I switched to or I started
taking on data science and machine learning a lot more seriously.
And I leveraged my software engineering experience to learn and implement
all of that.
And so today, what I do is I if I solve a machine learning
or an AI problem, I have my software engineering,
my best practices hat and I solve it from that perspective.
Interesting.
What would you say is some of the best practices that you feel
an agentic coder of today could very easily drop or miss when they're
when they're trying to build out their workflows and processes?
Yeah. So I was just one of the attendees here.
I just really addressed.
I think is very well into what we saying.
So what's happening is these days is we are reading less and we are passing
on the back over to the other side, which is non-deterministic.
We need to build and discipline ourselves to disturb
processes and steps and try to reduce the non-determinism.
So using a whole swarm of agents to build something
but then not knowing what it has built so you don't know how to use it.
And then that's where it's one of the things the other bit
is like not having a plan and just like, you know, vibe coding itself
is like just writing prompts after prompts isn't the greatest practice.
You plan your work.
So like I was telling the attendee that I remember Einstein's quote,
besides that, if you give me a problem and you give me an hour,
I'll spend 55 minutes
trying to think about the problem, trying to understand the problem,
and I'll spend five minutes trying to solve the problem.
Now, Einstein, great mind has done some great work or lots of great work.
We can learn something from that and then we can apply it in our space.
Yeah, yeah. Amazing.
What is some of the
what for example,
some of the sessions that you really took things — good practice.
So Guy's session kicked off really well — and I've got to name them.
But Patrick's session was amazing.
I would love to work with someone like Patrick who knows how
he needs to run, how teams need to be run while we are in the AI space.
Dave Farley really closed off well yesterday.
Yeah, and then there are some other sessions
where I took a little bits of, of of things like
pass on — do treat your current practices just like you were before AI came in.
Yeah. Don't don't drop those practices.
What what what we've been given is AI to augment our skills and not to
pass it on to AI to do all of the stuff and not know what's happening.
Yeah, because it's a great steer.
It's a great skill, great way to make us ten x.
But we need to be constantly disciplined, have a plan, have a structure
and use it in that manner and not slip away by a lot of people who are doing vibe
coding billions of lines of code and not knowing actually what has been created.
Yeah, basically.
Yeah. Amazing. Well, Manny, thank you very much for your time.
I'll let you get back to the hallway. I didn't
I So.
So the founder of NearForm.
Tell us a little bit about what you're learning here from attendees,
some of the conversations that you've had at the conference.
Oh my God, I.
Learned a lot about harness engineering.
Right. What? I've been here. It's crazy.
From when the conference was announced to now like it's become a thing.
Like, you know, it wasn't even a thing like, three months ago.
This is the horrible thing
about a CFP for a conference like this, because you open a CFP
and then something that happened, you know,
we opened it three, four months ago,
and the content and the things that are going to be hot,
you don't know what's going to be hot by the time the conference comes around.
So harness engineering first.
Engineering token mix.
Yeah.
And everyone's going like,
how are we going to afford to pay for this stuff in a few months time?
You know, and just a really vibrant community here, you know.
Yeah.
So obviously a consultancy that comes and helps people
in a very agentic way, which is, which is super, super cool
for a consultancy to really be pushing that.
Tell us a little bit about what some of the problems, some of the
some of the things that your clients and customers are asking from you these days.
Yeah, we're doing a combination
of having companies to start doing things in the agentic way.
You know, you have in most companies,
like 1 or 2 teams that are doing things in a more advanced way.
And it's like, how can I get to 100 teams?
So we're solving that problem for them.
So, you know, we're coming in.
We're doing kind of hands on training workshops building with the customers.
So we would technically,
you know, take a couple of lighthouse projects, work with our teams,
get them into kind of higher confidence level of what they're doing.
So just doing a bunch of stuff like that.
And then we're doing some applied AI stuff as well.
So we've [got an] interesting use case
for like an AML project with a financial institution.
So the AML department — you know,
like getting teams to do like KYC stuff and all that.
Like so getting agents to do that stuff recently.
So I think we, I think we cleared like a total of AML cases in 20 minutes.
Wow. Whereas that would have been about 3 to 4,000 hours of human time to do it
like you know.
Yeah.
Amazing opportunities for kind of like, you know, scaling
and being more efficient and effective with.
The other stuff we're seeing is around modernization.
So like,
we've a fun one with a client where a couple of years ago we were
unfortunate [enough for] a modernization project to be like
it was over €10 million project like big old code base.
Been around a long time.
And you know we we kind of spectacle pre-AI, and recently we've spent [time] enough
to doing it.
And it's coming in well under €2 million to do the same project
in about — wow — about
35% of the time.
So so like a seamless like a massive acceleration
in in a.
Reduction in the amount of time to do something.
Yeah. Yeah.
You know, so like we're seeing it from a consulting perspective like,
you know, this this huge opportunity you know.
Yeah. Yeah. Amazing.
How have you found the crowd here at AI Native DevCon? Oh, great.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Lovely community.
Like great people for us.
Yeah, yeah.
People are very nice here, you know? Amazing.
So I really, really enjoyed it.
Like. Yeah. Wonderful. Well thank you very much.
And thank you for all your support for DevCon. Thank you.
I think a really interesting diversity
in where people are at with their adoption of AI.
Yeah.
From the kind of cautious but curious end of the spectrum, through.
Are they kind of YOLO in it?
And I think my take on that is there's a lot of wisdom in both ends.
You know, people are rightly cautious with wisdom that's been hard
won over the years, and they're looking for something
that helps them to ensure that AI stays on the right track.
But to unleash the speed of AI
without just being kind of letting it do whatever and just accepting the risk.
Yeah.
And what do you say some of the in terms of these are I'm good.
What would you say are some of the, some of the biggest problems
that people have in their organizations today where, you know, a mature
security solution, which is very AI first, can kind of like help people with.
A lot of it comes down to trust.
Yeah.
And how you can.
Trust that things are going to stay on track
without having to be hands on and watching everything.
And so I think where Snyk has a lot to offer, there is is providing
the trust — is giving a solution that people can rely on, Snyk, to ensure
things don't go wrong with and don't feel like
they have to be hands on, you know, gripping the wheel really tightly.
Yeah.
At scale, I presume, as well as across the organization.
It's got a scale.
Yeah, it's got to scale. It's got to be codified.
It's got to be something that can fit the workflow again
without slowing things down. Yeah.
And actually integrated in the way that that flows.
Awesome. Great to see Snyk here.
Great to see you supporting the AI Native Dev community.
So I really really appreciate it. Amazing. Thank you very much.
here.
So, dear, tell us a little bit about AutonomyAI.
You're the founder and CEO, I believe.
CEO. Yes, yes. There we go. I didn't just promote you.
Did I? The founder and CEO of AutonomyAI.
Ali, tell us what AutonomyAI is.
So Fei is basically an operating system.
On existing codebases.
We enable
we understand existing codebases and understand
the components, the design system and all the design library.
And then we enable non-technical or semi-technical individuals.
Think about your PMs,
your designers, your professional services to be part of the delivery process.
Instead of going back and forth with engineering,
they can deliver everything end to end on your production code.
And what would you say?
Like some of the biggest differences between a non-technical person
and a technical person when it comes to, you know, them
doing work in the workflow, raising PRs, all that kind of thing.
What are the what are the differences in needs?
Well, let's start from the basic
the interface, all the workflow or all the interfaces you have to.
They are usually CLI interfaces.
Right.
And today what we enable is a web interface.
And it's super easy. That's the first thing.
The second thing, in order to actually push a PR
that is valid, viable and a consistent, reliable way.
The PMs don't know what the
what are the constraints of the platform itself, what AutonomyAI can help them with,
and what Fei Studio, our product, is helping them with is just click a button.
The pull request will understand the entire system.
PMs need to know how to ask visual things — KPIs on the product,
not how to build the code behind the scenes.
Super interesting.
Of course, we had Thomas, your CTO, here doing one of the sessions.
When you're talking with some of the folks
here at the booth or in sessions or on the hallway track.
What are what are people's biggest problems today that there
they're facing with their coding movement?
Everyone is spending so much money, right?
So much effort on this, but not actually seeing any needle movement.
Yes, the needle movement is very, very small.
Around 5 to 10%. Yeah.
And that's the main challenge.
And when we talk with people, we don't actually just talk about our product.
We talk about the actual workflow, where are the real bottlenecks.
And we start exposing these standards
that are not, you know, decoding velocity, writing code.
It's actually the workflow that you have within the organization.
And in one word, what is the
what is the thing that people should focus on,
that they're not spending enough time on.
Change management.
Utilize those tools not just to write things faster,
but actually how you can orchestrate your organization.
Change management. And we'll call that with a hyphen. All right.
what are the biggest problems that people in organizations
are having today in and around their own coding journey.
Who wants to take that one?
So we've been. Talking to.
People. Who.
Are getting very excited about agents and.
Then installing them all over the place and making lots and lots of skills,
and then they're a bit nervous about all the skills.
So they're either worried about security or they're worried about how they keep
track of all the different ones
and work out how to share them properly and do this track.
So I've been hearing that a lot from.
So, so sharing them through distribution, being able to actually validate them
and understand if they're good or if they're secure, those types of things.
Awesome.
Have you been to many sessions? I am.
Excited to go to my first session today.
Oh, which session are you going to
talk on?
Automation in GitHub?
Yeah.
I'm really looking forward to that
because I had a chat with him yesterday and he kind of gave me the gist.
And I think he has a point about GitHub and GitHub Actions
actually being a big, big part of automation in the future.
So I'm really curious to see what else he has to say
about how ready git and GitHub are for a coding workflow of today.
Would you say for a coding workflow of today?
Let me put this
contentious question to you.
I think.
They have the opportunity.
But being able to seize that is different.
What I mean by that is like when you've got the core primitives of
like an action is just basically running a workflow in the cloud
that the user is able to define.
And so that as a concept,
it feels very valuable when you've got an agent that you can now
run as part of that workflow in terms of the sequencing,
in terms of parking, in terms of branching.
But to be able to capitalize on that, they need to make sure that it's reliable
and it is effective and that they build the interfaces for people to do that,
particularly given that code is now so cheap that people can go
build their own versions themselves.
And so having the ease of onboarding, so much so that it is easier for me
to get an agent to use GitHub Actions rather than for me to go
have an agent write its own orchestrator on my own system.
I think it's kind of the important tension point there. Amazing.
And we'll wrap up with one final question about a very interesting early access
that Tessl announced here at Guy's session, in and around an agent harness.
Tell us a little bit about what that is, what people can expect.
Yeah.
So for the Tessl agent, I think the main framing is
people are going to need to shift up the abstraction
stack to be doing harness engineering, rather than just telling an agent
what to do.
And to do that effectively, you need to set up your environment
so that the agent can run effectively in that — you've got hooks,
you've got contexts, you've got verifiers,
you've got all these kind of core concepts that you can use to make sure the agent
is producing the correct code.
Tessl
is there to help you set up that environment and set up your ecosystem
and set up your codebase for success in it.
So it shifts your human leverage point to the point where you have the most value
in terms of defining how the agent should be operating,
rather than telling the agent what it should be doing, because that's
something that can be much tighter, much more easily encapsulated in a ticket.
Amazing.
And if you're interested in that, tessl.io/agent,
and you can learn more about how to get onto the early access list.
So that's a
wrap for AIND DevCon 2026 in London.
I'm here in the VIP room where we essentially let speakers
and some of our VIP attendees hang out.
Grab good coffee in nice comfort.
I'm pretty tired now.
My mind is absolutely full of amazing information from tons of great
speakers, tons of great conversations in the hallway track.
I think it's time to maybe have a little rest
and then start putting all that great knowledge into practice from tomorrow.
Thanks all for watching.
Thanks for attending and hopefully we'll see you in New York or London next year.
Bye for now.
The AI Native Dev is brought to you by the package manager for skills and context.
Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Our producer is Tom Dowler.
The AI Native Dev is not just a podcast, it's a community.
And we host monthly meetups at the Tessl offices in central London.
Visit tessl.io/community to learn more and I hope to see you there.